<Survey>
  <!-- The Short name is used when the survey is part of a list -->
  <ShortName> CO2D,CO</ShortName>
  
  <!-- This is a more complete descriptive name -->
  <Name>   CO Galactic Plane Survey</Name>
  
  <!-- A text description of the survey.  This may include HTML and
       if so would normally be included in a CDATA element. -->
  <Description>
   <![CDATA[
New large-scale CO surveys of the first and second Galactic quadrants and the 
nearby molecular cloud complexes in Orion and Taurus, obtained with the 
Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics 1.2 m telescope, have been 
combined with 31 other surveys obtained over the past two decades with that 
instrument and a similar telescope on Cerro Tololo in Chile, to produce a 
new composite CO survey of the entire Milky Way. The survey consists of 
488,000 spectra that Nyquist or beamwidth (1/8 deg) sample the entire Galactic 
plane over a strip 4 deg-10 deg wide in latitude, and beamwidth or 1/4 deg sample 
nearly all large local clouds at higher latitudes. Compared with the previous 
composite CO survey of Dame et al. (1987), the new survey has 16 times more 
spectra, up to 3.4 times higher angular resolution, and up to 10 times higher 
sensitivity per unit solid angle. 
<P>
Users should be aware that both the angular resolution and the 
sensitivity varies from region to region in the velocity-integrated map.
The component surveys were integrated individually using clipping or 
moment masking in order to display nearly all statistically significant 
emission but little noise above a level of ~1.5 K km/s. See the reference 
below and the 
<a href="http://cfa-www.harvard.edu/cfa/mmw/MilkyWayinMolClouds.html" >
Millimeter-Wave Group site</a> for  more details
   ]]>
  </Description>

  <Settings>
    <Scale> 0.125    </Scale>
  </Settings>
  
  <!-- The MetaTable includes a set of standard metadata about the survey -->
  <MetaTable>
    <Provenance> Data taken by two nearly-identical 1.2 m 
       telescopes in Cambridge, MA and on Cerro Tololo, Chile  combined into a 
       complete survey of the Milky Way with CO integrated over all velocities.  
    </Provenance>
    <Copyright> Permission is granted for publication and
      reproduction of this material for research or educational purposes so 
      long as the reference (see below) is included.
     </Copyright>
    <Regime>           Radio        </Regime>
    <NSurvey>          1            </NSurvey>
    <Frequency>        115 GHz      </Frequency>
    <Bandpass>         114.89 - 115.12 GHz </Bandpass>
    <Coverage>         All galactic longitudes, irregular bands between -35 and +35 latitudes
    </Coverage>
    <PixelScale>       0.125d/pixel </PixelScale>
    <PixelUnits>       Pixel values are velocity-integrated main beam brightness temperature, in units of K km/s</PixelUnits>
    <CoordinateSystem> Galactic     </CoordinateSystem>
    <Projection>       Rectangular  </Projection>
    <Epoch>            1980 to 2000 </Epoch>
    <Reference> 
      <![CDATA[
       <a href="http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2001ApJ...547..792D">Dame, T. M., Hartmann, Dap, Thaddeus, P., <i>ApJ</i>, 2001 (ADS)</a>
      ]]>
    </Reference>
  </MetaTable>
  
  <!-- Online text is displayed in a HTML rendering of output.
       The online text can include the special strings $ra,$dec and $size
       which are replaced by the J2000 RA, J2000 Dec or size in degrees
       of the search just completed.  If online text is present
       it will usually contain XML and should be within a CDATA element.
    -->
  <OnlineText/>

  <!-- The text included in the FITS element should be added to the FITS
       header for the image generated by the file.  Note that we
       do not include the MetaTable information which may be extracted
       from the MetaTable elements.  We include the FITS element in
       a CDATA to preserve any special characters and spacing
    -->
  <FITS>
<![CDATA[
SURVEY  = 'CO      '
TELESCOP= 'MULTIPLE'                                                           
BUNIT   = 'KM/S-1  ' 
HISTORY ------------------------------------------------------------------------
HISTORY Sixteen separate surveys of the J = 1 to 0 transition of CO at
HISTORY 115 GHz, obtained with nearly identical 1.2 m telescopes in New
HISTORY York City and on Cerro Tololo, Chile, have been combined into a
HISTORY complete survey of the Milky Way. All data were placed on a uniform     
HISTORY grid with 0.5 deg spacing in Galactic longitude and latitude,
HISTORY and 1.3 km/s spacing in velocity.  The composite CO survey is        
HISTORY contained in 720 latitude-velocity maps, for longitude 0 deg to         
HISTORY 359.5 deg, spaced every 0.5 deg. To simplify the construction           
HISTORY of data cubes, the latitude and velocity limits for all 720 maps        
HISTORY are identical:  from -25 deg to +25 deg in latitude and from
HISTORY -299.7 to +299.7 km/s in velocity.  This map is a single longitude-
HISTORY latitude map of CO integrated over all velocities.
HISTORY                                                                         
HISTORY ------------------------------------------------------------------------
HISTORY                                                                         
HISTORY Permission is granted for publication and reproduction of this          
HISTORY material for research or educational purposes so long as the            
HISTORY following reference is included.                                        
HISTORY 
HISTORY Dame, T. M., Ungerechts, H., Cohen, R. S., de Geus, E. J.,              
HISTORY Grenier, I. A., May, J., Murphy, D. C., Nyman, L.-A., and               
HISTORY Thaddeus, P., ApJ, 322, 706                                             
HISTORY                                                                         
]]>
  </FITS>
  
  <!-- The Images area includes descriptors of the images in the survey
       and replaces the config file in the previous version of SkyView.
       Each Image line has 4 tokens: filename, J2000 RA, J2000 Dec and
       Epoch of the image.
    -->
  <Images>
    <!-- The Image factory is the name of a class implementing the ImageFactory
         interface that can be used to create an image given the full
	 file name. -->
    <ImageFactory>
         skyview.survey.CachingImageFactory
    </ImageFactory>
    
    <!-- The image size gives the minimum dimension of an image. -->
    <ImageSize>360 </ImageSize>
    <Image>http://skyview.gsfc.nasa.gov/surveys/co2d/co_2000x.fits,co_2000x.fits,1480,280,Car,G,2961,561,.125,.125 266.434 -28.936 1990</Image>
  </Images>
</Survey>
