<Survey>
  <!-- The Short name is used when the survey is part of a list -->
  <ShortName>NEAT, NEAT/SkyMorph</ShortName>
  
  <!-- This is a more complete descriptive name -->
  <Name>Near-Earth Asteriod Tracking System Archive</Name>
  
  <!-- A text description of the survey.  This may include HTML and
       if so would normally be included in a CDATA element. -->
  <Description>
   <![CDATA[
The NEAT/SkyMorph survey provides access to the archives
of the Near Earth Asteroid Tracking (NEAT) project.  NEAT is
designed to look for potentially hazardous asteroids, i.e., those
whose orbits cross the Earth's.  Over 200,000 images are available
in the NEAT archive.  
<a href=http://skys.gsfc.nasa.gov/skymorph/skymorph.html>SkyMorph</a>
provides a Web interface to the NEAT
images and allows users to select all images in which a given fixed
or moving object is found.
<p>
Unlike most <i>SkyView</i> surveys, the NEAT data are extremely irregular in their
spatial distribution.  <i>SkyView</i>'s algorithms for mosaicking images
together to form large images are not adequate for the NEAT data, so
mosaicking is surpressed.  Only data within a single NEAT image will
be displayed.  The system attempts to find the most recent image within
which has a offset in both RA and Dec of less than 0.8 degrees.  If no
such image is found, then an image with the minimum offset is returned, or
the search may fail altogether if there are no nearby plates.
The NEAT telescope uses an array of 4 CCDs.  The backgrounds of the 
CCDs may differ significantly.
<p>

The NEAT survey covers approximately 30% of the sky.  Extreme southern
and low-Galactic latitude regions are unsurveyed.  Coverage is otherwise
particularly dense in the ecliptic plane.
<p>
NEAT data consists primarily of groups of three images taken with separations
of 20 minutes and almost identical positions.  <i> SkyView </i> will normally
return the last of a 'triplet'.  The SkyMorph site can be used to display
an overlay of triplets to look for targets which moved during the interval
between images.
<p>
A catalog of objects detected in the NEAT/SkyMorph pages is accessible
through the SkyMorph pages.  'Light-curves' from all images during which
an object was in the NEAT field of view can also be generated.
<P>
The NEAT data values are in arbitrary density units.  To enhance the display
data are transformed such that all pixels below the median values
are scaled linearly to values 0-20, while all pixels above the median
are shifted (but not scaled) to values greater than 20.
    ]]>
  </Description>
  
  <!-- These settings are used where the user may not have made an explicit selection
       and where no system defaults exist.
    -->
  <Settings>
    <!-- The scale of this image -->
    <Scale> 0.0004 </Scale>
  </Settings>
  
  <!-- The MetaTable includes a set of standard metadata about the survey -->
  <MetaTable>
<Provenance> 
    <![CDATA[
	<a href="http://huey.jpl.nasa.gov/~spravdo/neat.html">NEAT project</a>
    ]]>
    </Provenance> 
    <Copyright>
    <![CDATA[
See the <a href="http://www.jpl.nasa.gov/images/policy/index.html">JPL Image Use Policy</a>
    ]]>
    </Copyright>
    <Regime>      Optical    </Regime>
    <NSurvey>     1          </NSurvey>
    <Frequency>   500 THz    </Frequency>
    <Bandpass>    374-750 THz </Bandpass>
    <Coverage>    Patches of the sky, approximately 30% coverage </Coverage>
    <PixelScale>  1.42"      </PixelScale>
    <PixelUnits>             </PixelUnits>
    <Resolution>  Depends on image. Typically 1.5" </Resolution>
    <Coordinates> Equatorial </Coordinates>
    <Equinox>     2000       </Equinox> 
    <Projection>  Radially distorted gnomonic </Projection>>
    <Epoch>       1995-2006  </Epoch>

    <Reference>
<![CDATA[ href=http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/1999AJ...117.1616P> Pravdo, et al. 1999 (ADS) </a>
]]>
    </Reference>
  </MetaTable>
  
  <!-- Online text is displayed in a HTML rendering of output.
       The online text can include the special strings $ra,$dec and $size
       which are replaced by the J2000 RA, J2000 Dec or size in degrees
       of the search just completed.  If online text is present
       it will usually contain XML and should be within a CDATA element.
    -->
  <OnlineText/>

  <!-- The text included in the FITS element should be added to the FITS
       header for the image generated by the file.  Note that we
       do not include the MetaTable information which may be extracted
       from the MetaTable elements.  We include the FITS element in
       a CDATA to preserve any special characters and spacing
    -->
  <FITS>
<![CDATA[
SURVEY  = 'NEAT    '
BUNIT   Scaled densities                                                        
HISTORY The NEAT/SkyMorph survey provides access to the archives of the 
HISTORY Near Earth Asteroid Tracking (NEAT) project. NEAT is
HISTORY designed to look for potentially hazardous asteroids, i.e., those 
HISTORY whose orbits cross the Earth's. Over 50,000 images are available 
HISTORY in the NEAT archive.
HISTORY Unlike most SkyView surveys, the NEAT data are extremely irregular 
HISTORY in their spatial distribution. SkyView's algorithms for mosaicking
HISTORY images together to form large images are not adequate for the 
HISTORY NEAT data, so mosaicking is surpressed. Only data within a 
HISTORY single NEAT image will be displayed. The system attempts to find 
HISTORY the most recent image within which has a offset in both RA and Dec of
HISTORY less than 0.4 degrees. If no such image is found, then an image 
HISTORY with the minimum offset is returned, or the search may fail altogether 
HISTORY if there are no nearby plates. The NEAT telescope uses an array of 
HISTORY 4 CCDs. The backgrounds of the CCDs may differ significantly. 
HISTORY
HISTORY The NEAT survey covers approximately 30% of the sky. Extreme 
HISTORY southern and low-Galactic latitude regions are unsurveyed.
HISTORY Coverage is otherwise particularly dense in the ecliptic plane. 
HISTORY
HISTORY NEAT data consists primarily of groups of three images taken with 
HISTORY separations of 20 minutes and almost identical positions. SkyView
HISTORY will normally return the last of a 'triplet'. The SkyMorph site can 
HISTORY be used to display an overlay of triplets to look for targets which
HISTORY moved during the interval between images. 
HISTORY A catalog of objects detected in the NEAT/SkyMorph pages is 
HISTORY accessible through the SkyMorph pages. 'Light-curves' from 
HISTORY all images during which an object was in the NEAT field of view can 
HISTORY also be generated. 
HISTORY
HISTORY The NEAT data values are in arbitrary density units. To enhance 
HISTORY the display data are transformed such that all pixels below the
HISTORY median values are scaled linearly to values 0-20, while all pixels 
HISTORY above the median are shifted (but not scaled) to values greater 
HISTORY than 20. 
]]>
  </FITS>
  <Images>
    <!-- The File Prefix, if present, is prepended to every file name -->
    <!-- The Siap keywords are used by the SIAPGenerator and illustrate how
         we use the Settings to pass information needed only in
	 some specialized circumnstances.  This is also why we probably
	 don't write a Schema for this format!
	 -->
    <SiapURL>
<![CDATA[
http://skyview.gsfc.nasa.gov/cgi-bin/vo/sia_skm.pl?FORMAT=image/fits&
]]>
    </SiapURL>
    
    <SiapProjection>  Tan   </SiapProjection>
    <SiapCoordinates> J2000 </SiapCoordinates>
    <SiapMaxImages>   1     </SiapMaxImages>
    
    <!-- The Image factory is the name of a class implementing the ImageFactory
         interface that can be used to create an image given the full
	 file name. -->
    <ImageFactory>
         skyview.survey.CachingImageFactory
    </ImageFactory>
    
    <!-- The image size gives the minimum dimension of an image. -->
    <ImageSize> 1.5 </ImageSize>
    
    <ImageGenerator>skyview.survey.NeatGenerator</ImageGenerator>
    
  </Images>
</Survey>
